we're in 2024 and I still find to this
day people that have been trading in the
markets for 6 years and are not
profitable while on the meantime I have
new Traders which are my students that
are not only profitable but making five
figures a month so what's the difference
and the difference I'm going to describe
in this video which are the next point
that I'm going to explain to you so make
sure you watch the video all the way to
the end because if you're a new Trader
you can learn from it if you're an old
Trader you can change your ways and
become this new Trader mindset that a
lot of them are becoming successful UC
ful really really fast and also if
you're a new Trader let me know in the
comments below if this is what you
actively use right now so first things
first is back in the day sounds crazy
for me to say that but it's like back in
the day when I got started there was a
ginormous lack of information there was
a huge opportunity which was being able
to become a day trader but there wasn't
a lot of people out there expressing and
sharing their experiences with this
opportunity it was a very new early on
thing and nobody kind knew that you can
become successful by making this your
day job or making it your full-time
occupation and there was a lack of
information that a lot of people simply
didn't know it was there and only a very
small group of people decided to go out
there and explain their journey and
educate people on how to do it so this
was good but also bad because the
information that actually got out there
was actually valuable so the people that
were educating at that time were real
people with real experiences sharing it
real time at that point where you can
actually learn from but it's also bad
because since it wasn't normalized in
society and it wasn't something that a
lot of people were doing you were also
extremely skeptical about it and you
didn't believe in the fact that it's
possible and honestly the way that
people would educate and teach wouldn't
be ideal it's a very outdated version on
how to do it compared to how nowadays in
201 24 there is so much information out
there that you can literally grasp on to
anyone that obviously looks good makes
sense and you can genuinely become
profitable and this is what the new
Traders are doing because there is so
much information out there that your
personality can connect with any one of
these different types of Educators in
the space and it's a lot easier for you
to learn and for you to be able to apply
these strategies or these Market
approaches into the market every single
day where back in the day when there was
only five six seven guys you just had to
adapt yourself to that person and
everything around them now you have
hundreds of people to select from which
is also kind of of a double-edged sword
because it can be a little bit of
information overload and you not knowing
who you want to choose where to start
who to listen to and can you piece
people's information together so we're
at that point right now where it's a
little bit of an information overload
but this is is only meant for those new
traders that are able to filter out the
[__] so if you're able to filter out
what is literally not good and what has
a red flag in front of it and only focus
on what is legit consistent and
transparent then you're able to actually
utilize that in your favor because
you're only focusing on what matters and
removing all of the other noise and
these new traders in 2024 are pretty
much mastered that and this is what has
led them to success and part of of
filtering out this information they have
to do this in their own environment
which is my next point that all of these
Traders it's kind of cool because they
all create their own trading space they
create their own little corner in a room
a spot in the kitchen um maybe a closet
that they turned into their own office
or honestly in your room in front of
your bed but they have like their own
designated spot where they go to every
single day to apply the trading plan to
go watch videos like these and get
educated to take the trade
to practice your rituals to cope with
your losses or celebrate your wins they
have their own little designated spot
that they can literally dedicate their
own time into to themselves where they
can put time into this craft and I say
this is extremely important because
you're in a niche and you're in a
different type of business that it's you
versus you and you're the only one
that's going to be able to see if you're
doing something right or doing something
wrong you're going to be the only able
one to hold yourself self accountable
when you're doing something wrong and
celebrate their wins when you're doing
something right no one's going to
understand your journey that you're
going through and no one's going to
resonate and connect with it other than
you so if you have your own little
environment your own desk uh your own
section this is where you feel
comfortable this is where you feel at
peace this is where you feel 100% laser
focused in for you to apply the strategy
and for you to learn what the market is
giving you and you can put to practice
the skills that you're actively putting
into the markets every single day and
this little space of yours is what's
going to take you to the next level
because Without You realizing you having
this little space of yours you're
putting a routine into your every single
day life and this routine is key to not
only succeeding in trading but learning
from your losses and then obviously
repeating your wins and that leads me to
the next point and that is that all of
these new Traders become a Trader let me
explain to you what that means because
that might probably go right over your
head in order for you to become let's
say a bodybuilder you have to actually
become a bodybuilder like oh no [__]
Alex obviously no no no like I don't
think you understand like you literally
need to become one of these guys like
you have to show up every single day hit
every rep as hard as you can have the
diet make sure that you're doing the
cardio make sure that you're stretching
you you have to practice every aspect of
it in order to become a bodybuilder
there's no cheating there's no halfway
out well these guys are doing the exact
same thing but in trading they're having
their trading routine they're going
they're showing up every single day
they're learning from the losses they're
watching videos like these they're doing
everything a Trader needs to do in order
to become a Trader dude I was working at
Dunkin Donuts 6 years ago and never in
my life did I expect myself to pick up a
book and read when my parents saw me
reading a book about trading they their
mind literally just they they just were
like what what is this like what's wrong
with this guy these guys that I
personally know myself in high school
that were smoking weed that were
skipping school and just not being the
person that I thought they would ever
become I look at them now and they're a
traitor they have routine they cut off
all had they cut off all bad habits they
cut off bad people like they became this
new person in order for you to become a
successful Trader you have have to
become this new person the person that
you go into trading is not the same
person that you are when you come out of
there because the pressure that you go
into as a Trader and the different types
of battles that you're going to face
nothing can prepare you for that and
nobody will ever be able to literally
transfer that experience over to you
unlike you doing it yourself and that is
what a lot of these Traders have
listened to the suggestion of people
like me and other people people that
tell you you're about to enter a battle
and they get ready for that battle and
when they're going through it they're
embracing the whole journey of it and
they're becoming who they have to become
because with those bad habits of you
smoking weed and with you not practicing
a routine you are simply not going to
cut it it's just not going to happen I
guarantee you and I'm not talking about
just smoking weed in specific I know
people out there that smoke weed and are
successful by all means talking about my
personal experience and other people
that I've seen that have cut out all
these bad habits and now they're in
these new rituals that I am literally
dumbfounded by the fact that who they've
become into but they've become into a
Trader and that's truthfully what you
need at the end of the day to become
successful in this space and when I mean
become a Trader I don't mean that you
have to like meditate in the morning or
light a candle I don't do that myself I
never did it in my whole entire trading
journey I didn't even attempt it like
that's just not who I am it's not
authentic to me but what I mean is more
of like the things that you're willing
to do in order to become successful and
the things that you're willing to repeat
every single day until you become
successful whether it's reading a book
every single day whether it's watching
videos every single day whether it's
going to sleep late waking up early or
waking up late falling asleep early like
all of these things that you just apply
every single day until you get
successful which is part of the journey
and part of the process wherever you are
in the world whatever session you trade
it's just like the like throwing all
these things together together in order
to become successful is what it is it's
not all these different types of
stereotypes that you have to do in order
to become a Trader no none of that at
all and most importantly is that you are
only focusing on being a Trader you're
not focusing on doing e-commerce Drop
Shipping you're not focused on FBA
you're not focused on uh whatever else
that you want to be like your only focus
is a Trader I want to become a Trader so
you put all your eggs in one basket in
that that is it it either works out for
you because you did everything right or
it doesn't because you slacked off
halfway all of these people that I know
every single newbie that I've seen they
said I was going to do this until I was
successful I had no other option I
either became successful in this or I'm
[__] and when somebody tells me I
literally get goosebumps cuz I'm like
bro this guy has it in him and you got
to have that you got to have that hint
inside of you you got to have that fire
inside of you that's going to take you
to that point and L not focus on
anything else other than your one
objective and that is to become a Trader
so now I want to explain to you the
number one technical thing that I've
seen a lot of these new Traders do and
when I found out I was like wow that is
[__] creative I would have never
thought about that at the beginning but
it makes total sense because you're just
eliminating one literally eliminating
half of the work that I would be doing
at the beginning or that a lot of these
Traders were doing at the beginning
because you're eliminating a lot of
noise it's going to sound a little bit
crazy but it just works and that is that
Traders are only now focusing on buys
that's it right isn't that kind of crazy
like they are only focusing on taking a
buy position now what do I mean by that
that means that they Master the art of
reading the market in bullish sequence
obviously in higher highs and higher
lows now you're probably asking yourself
what if the market is bearish well all
they do is flip the chart there is one
click away that you have to right click
on trading view click invert scale and
the chart will automatically flip around
what does that do well now the market
that was selling now it looks like it's
buying and you can apply the same exact
strategy but now on a buy position
obviously the only difference is when
you go execute the trade instead of
clicking buy you would click sell but
you're analyzing the market as if it
were to be a buy for some reason us
humans we have this little dilemma and
we see some things clearer than other
things even though it might be the same
exact thing and Traders usually they
have a lot of difficulties
differentiating a buy from a sell they
can see sells sometimes a little bit
messy but they can see buys extremely
clear well what if I told you that
there's a hack to always look at buys
all you have to do is flip the chart and
you can see the same exact thing that
you would be seeing if the market were
to be a buy the moment I found out about
this I was like wow I've been well
obviously in the beginning I lost so
much time trying to figure out a
strategy for sell and a strategy for a
buy when it's the same exact thing all
you have to do is just flip the chart
and analyze it that way you're saving
yourself 50% of the time trying to
figure out if it makes more sense sense
to sell than to buy all you're doing is
flipping the chart and looking at the
exact same pattern that you were to look
to if it were to be a buy and that's
because the mind just works in a way
where us humans think that things are
going to go up when we enter a market we
wanted to buy right whenever we think of
the stock market or we think of crypto
Bitcoin we think buy up nobody ever
thinks of sell down nobody's ever really
grasped that con everybody thinks
something when you buy it supposed to go
up the value of your house when you buy
it you expect for it to go up the value
of a car you would hope for you to buy
and it would go up a watch you buy it
goes up we never buy something or we
never invest into something with the
mindset that it's going to go down and
nonetheless think that you're going to
make money when it goes down it just
logically does not make sense in our
mind it's just the way how we've been
brought up over the years it's not our
fault it's our parents fault so if
you're not a good seller theying not
your parents and you should subscribe
the button because of that CU it's just
funny so hit the Subscribe button but
back to examples us humans just simply
understand the concept of always buying
something for it to go up or whenever we
invest money into something we never
think of us betting that it's going to
go down with that being said now on step
two which is on the technical aspect and
this is going to kind of hit a lot of
you know new beginner trainers like
right in the heart and that is to not
focus on the entry signal I cannot
explain to you how many of you guys
comment on my videos what is the entry
signal what is the entry signal how do I
know when to answer how do I know this
and that is literally the last step this
is what the new beginners have finally
mastered and that is that entering the
trade is not the main focus it is
everything you do before entering the
trade for example let's say you're going
to invest into a real estate property
not going to ask an investor how do I
buy the property like how do I buy where
do I sign where do I get a loan like
that's not the first thing you're going
to do the first thing you need to do in
order for this to be a successful
transaction and you make money with it
is is it in a right location does it
have potential to go up in value does it
need renovation is there a possible
rental is it a good flip like you need
to think about all the things behind the
scenes first to see if it even makes
sense to make make this investment on
this real estate property you're not
going to just go into real estate
investing and be like how do I buy it
where do I send the money that's how
you're going to lose a [__] ton of money
that just doesn't work you need to do
the logistical backend work first in
order for the deal to make sense same
thing in trading you can't think about
entering a trade without you knowing how
to read the market first first you got
to learn how to read the market what is
the market telling you are we going up
or are we going down are we at a good
area to buy are we good an area to sell
are we having my trading plan check out
are we not like you need to First
understand what is the market doing
before you enter the trade and these new
Traders they've mastered the Arts of
focusing on everything but the entry
signal and leaving that for last cuz
obviously the entry point is the point
of execution and everybody wants to know
how do you do that or where should you
enter but you need to make sure that
first the trade
even overall makes sense because
entering a trade is literally the last
thing and that takes me to step number
three that as soon as you know how to
enter the trade and as soon as you
figured out all of this stuff out you
don't want to back test this [__] you
don't want to waste time going and back
testing you're going to take this livee
right away that is exactly what these
new beginner trades do they literally
either go deposited money into their own
Live account or they go and get funded
immediately they waste no time now this
is key because you put a lot of things
to test here you put to test your
trading plan you put to test your
concept your risk management your routin
you put everything to test immediately
versus if you think you got it figure it
out and then you go to back test and
then you waste two three months back
testing and trying to add and renovate
and move around and just simply just
waste time these new Traders they are
not wasting time these guys want to be
successful today so what do they do they
put it to test today and the moment they
put it to test they put it to work every
single day until they succeed they're
not wasting any time back testing
something that happened 2 years ago when
they have the opportunity to execute on
it today and this is something that I
have always pushed and something that I
personally did myself I never back
tested one day in my life there was not
one day probably like a day or two just
to see how that tool work but I did not
back test anything from the moment that
I figured out how to execute a trade and
for me to think that I was right I was
executing a trade now cost me a lot of
money at the beginning cost me 2 years
of losses and thousands of dollars in
losses but I'm telling you that it
definitely paid out because I learned
from those mistakes and I was able to
physically feel what it felt like to
lose money into something that I thought
it was 100% right you can never have
that same feeling if you're back testing
it just won't happen the feeling that
you get from losing and the feeling you
get from from winning is what builds
character and it builds you that person
as a Trader that you literally need to
become in order to be successful now
moving on to step four they understand
that less is more now this is a very
difficult concept for a new person to
grasp and honestly I am surprised that a
lot of these Traders grasped at the
beginning because when I see you guys in
person I like talking to you guys and I
like understanding what are you doing
how are you doing it do you get this do
you not get this is how long have you
been doing it and they understand that
the less they do in the markets and the
less they're involved the more money
they're going to make they understand
that trading is not like a job it's not
something that you show up every single
day and say all right I'm clocking in
today and I'm a clock out at this time
and I'm going to make that much money
for putting in that much work the market
owes me money because I put time into it
no that is not how this works at all
they understand that you make money in
the market by making the right decisions
and sometimes those right decisions you
don't have to do it every day or every
other day or sometimes even every week
you only do it when it's the right time
to make a right decision now those right
decisions come less than often than you
would expect that's why in order for you
to be successful as a newb Trader less
is more you don't have to make that
decision every single day you can make
it whenever the market gives you the
opportunity to make that decision and by
making more of the right decisions and
less of the wrong decisions you make
more money now this is something you
grasp over time and obviously repetition
and just simply stowing up every single
day and making the wrong decisions a lot
of times will teach you this but these
guys figured it out very fast that they
don't have to learn by taking losses
they just learn by only focusing on
taking Le wins and that the less time
that they actually spend on the markets
they make more money now this is a
little bit of reverse psychology or
reverse engineering and it's you have to
put in the time at the beginning but
after you put in the time you don't have
to put in the time it's like if you want
to become a pilot you have to put in
your 400 hours or however many hours it
is to become a pilot so you get your
certification but then after that you
kind of don't forget that skill you can
then go fly one a year once every two
months and you know exactly what you're
doing but at the beginning in order for
you to get that certification you had to
put in that time well it's the same
exact thing with trading now moving on
to step five and this is by far the most
hack and cheat code that I wish I had
when I began trading and it's become the
normal for all of these new Traders and
they have killed this concept and they
have grasped it and ran with it and they
have even banged up a lot of these
companies and that is that a lot of
these Traders are not trading their own
money they're getting funded these guys
are literally passing these challenges
left and right they're making this [__]
look [__] easy I think I was
personally one of the first people to
come across prop firms in around 209
2020 and I was extremely skeptical about
it at the time because I didn't believe
that they were real or that they worked
out and obviously after time I gave it a
shot and obviously got my first payout
and then it just started getting more
normalized in the industry but there
wasn't that many different offers and
the challenges were actually extremely
difficult at that time with very limited
time and very hard take profits now
these Traders are getting access to 10
times more of the money that I did when
I got started and the challenges are a
hundred times easier you have unlimited
time smaller take profits you can use
EAS in your advantage you can do so many
different things to actually get funded
so a lot of these Traders are not using
their own money so they pretty much have
a lot more bank roll than you can
imagine because imagine that you were to
be a new beginner Trader and you come
into the markets and you would have
$22,000 to invest into the market well
if you were to start when I did that's
all you had all you had was $2,000 to
start with that's it you had to make
something out of those
$2,000 but let's say you were to go to
Rocka 21 with those $2,000 you can split
it up in different types of payments you
can get a 100K challenge for 400 bucks
for $400 you can get access to $100,000
let's say you fail the challenge about
two three times and on the fourth one
you get it you just got access to
$100,000 that you would have never
gotten access to with the first 2,000 if
you would have initially started off
with it so you have a lot more bankroll
than you can ever imagine and by you
taking on this challenge you're forcing
yourself to follow a trading plan you're
forcing yourself to follow risk
management rules because the prop firms
have minimum drw down and minimum weekly
minimum total risk and you have a take
profit so you're working towards a goal
with x amount of time like you are
literally forced to become a successful
Trader evaluation process on Rocket 21
is 8% on stage 1 and 8% on stage two
when I got started you had 30 days on
stage one 60 days on stage two Now
Rocket 21 you have unlimited time
meaning you you can take your sweet time
to get funded and on top of that you
keep more of the money rocket 21 has
about a 90% profit split I got 70 so it
was a lot harder to make money back then
and it wasn't normalized versus now you
can literally leverage
$400 like nobody could have ever done it
5 years ago and on top of that it's a
lot more normalized in the industry so
you have a lot more to pick from a lot
more ways to actually approach the
funding route compared to before where
it's just retail now to put this into
simple perspective imagine you would
have put those $2,000 into your own Live
account and you were to make 10% of that
you'd have made 200 bucks you're not
paying [__] with 200 bucks you're barely
paying the light bill and let's say you
would have gotten $400 out of those
2,000 and you would have bought a
challenge past got funded and then you
made the same
10% now you just made
$10,000 out of nothing out of $400 that
once you pass the challenge they give
you a refund plus your 90% profit split
you just made
$99,000 plus your money back with no
risk associated taking the same exact
trades making the same exact percentage
it is the cheat code of the century and
I'm not saying that it's easier because
let's say you failed the first time
let's say you failed the second time the
third the fourth and you got it on the
fifth dude you just got access to more
money that you would have ever gotten to
if you would have flipped those 2,00 0 5
times you have more money than you can
have ever touched in your life with the
same starting balance so if you guys
want to check out the easiest evaluation
process in the industry to today go
check out rocket 21 challenge.com so I
recommend 10 out of 10 and honestly your
access to become a new be successful
Trader has gotten a whole lot easier and
that takes me to step six and that is
that new Traders understand risk
management everybody's dream as a Trad
traders to come into the market and flip
$11,000 into $10,000 turn $100 into a
million which I tried that failed
horribly but at least I tried and they
understand that just because it's
available out there to them it doesn't
mean that it's sustainable they've
accepted the fact that they can attempt
this they can take a try at trying to
flip an account and it's possible but
they know that it's not sustainable they
understand that the art of flipping an
account is not something that you can do
every single day every single week or
rely on to actually make money in the
markets in order for you to actually
make money in the market you need to
have a proper risk management strategy
you can't just show up into the market
and decide today I'm going to risk 50%
of my account or I'm going to risk
whatever money you decide to or this
trade I think it's good so I risk more
the next trade I think it's eh so I risk
less no no no that [__] does not fly
that [__] does not work you pick one
percentage that you decide to take and
every single trade is exactly the same
you do not modify the percentage more or
less you do not change the type of trade
for more or less it is the same exact
thing every single time and this risk
management strategy that
99% actually [__] that 100% of all these
new be Traders are using is what takes
them to that next point because you can
have the best strategy in the world you
can have the best entry the best trend
continuation the the best everything and
if you do not have proper risk
management you will not succeed and this
is now become the normal IND industry
and Traders understand that you need it
at the beginning when I got started you
didn't need that everybody was just
flipping accounts turning this into this
taking this to this and that was
something that was normalized back then
and that's what Traders were making a
living out of little did I know that
none of that [__] was ever sustainable
just because the possibili is out there
to do it does not mean you can do it
every single day as time started going
on Traders started to actually realize
that it's not real and they built a
standard percentage per trade whether
it's going to be 1% 2% 3% Max it should
ever be is 4% per trade and you stick to
that every single trade never do you
ever want to risk 2% on one trade and
after you win then you want to double
that percent to 4% you never want to do
that because if you lose that trade not
only do you just lose all the money you
made on the first trade but you lose the
percentage that you would have
originally taken you need to risk the
same percentage on every single trade
whether you're on a five win trade or
whether you're on a 10 loss trade you
never want to chase any type of trade by
risking more more money to make back x
amount of money that is how you enter a
downward spiral of just p&l that's all
over the place you want to have the same
exact percentage that you risk per every
single trade now might sound like a
broken record repeating this time and
time again but I am telling you right
now this is the key to becoming
successful because even if you have a
30% win rate literally out of 10 trades
you only win three of them which is very
hard to only have a 30% win rate like
you actually have to suck and if you
suck that bad and you have a 30% win
rate and you have a good risk management
strategy you are still profitable and
that is because out of the three trades
that you win you're going to have a 1
to3 risk her reward ratio meaning for
every single trade that you lose you
lose 1% and for every single trade that
you win you win
3% so out of that three trades that you
have just won you won 3% per trade so
it' be 3
69 and let's say you lost seven trades
in a row you just lost 7% so with the 9%
you just won you made back the 7% losses
and you stayed 2% positive now let's say
that you were to risk 2% on one win and
then 5% on one loss and and then 1% on
another win and then the rest are losses
you're not going to ever be successful
because your p&l is not structured it's
not the same if you have the same
percentage that you risk and the same
risk to reward I can guarantee you you
will be successful even if you are the
shittiest Trader on the face of the
Earth guaranteed and this isn't matter
if you're a newbie Trader like 90% of my
students or if you're an OG Trader like
myself you need a strategy to follow
that is why 90% of the new successful
traders in the industry are with the set
and forget strategy because it is the
simplest strategy that teaches Traders
how to make anywhere from ,000 to
$1,500 a week as a beginner set and
forget Trader and you're probably
wondering what C foret is and how does
it make people with this money there's a
video in the link in the description
below that explains to you exactly what
it is completely for free just watch the
video so you can see how Traders can
make anywhere from 1,000 to 1,500 $ a
week as a beginner set and forget Trader
this way you can see how newb Traders
are now killing it and you can actually
get on a call with me every single
Sunday so I can make sure your success
is guaranteed along with everything that
I teach you on a live call appreciate
you guys watching this video all the way
to the end make sure to like comment and
subscribe and I'll see you inside s
don't forget